Tochukwu Uzochukwu

Experienced software developer with a background of building web applications using different tools, frameworks and technologies. Skilled at writing well-designed, testable and efficient code using current best practices in web development.

Email: tolexreal7@gmail.com. Github: github.com/4tolexx. Twitter: twitter.com/4tolexx.

EXPERIENCE

Velaluqa GmbH, Berlin Germany — *software developer* March 2022 - PRESENT

- Developed and maintained web applications using ruby and rails.
- Improved test suite performance on the CI by reducing the time taken to run jobs from 40 minutes to approximately 9 minutes.
- Implemented feature for user impersonation using the pretender library.
- Implemented a middleware functionality that displays a maintenance page during website downtime.
- Implemented background jobs processing functionality using sidekiq library.
- Worked with containerisation technologies e.g docker.
- Ensured improved test coverage for web applications using rspec-rails, turnip and capybara libraries etc.

Creative Works, Lagos Nigeria — *backend developer* February 2020 - November 2021

- Developed and maintained web applications using python and django
- Applied agile principles to ship products in a fast-paced startup etc.

TECHNOLOGIES/SKILLS

- Python.
- Django.
- Ruby.
- Rails.
- Docker.
- Elixir(hobby).
- Phoenix.
- Git.
- HTML and CSS.
- Linux.
- PostgreSQL.

EDUCATION

University of Nigeria, Enugu — Bachelors of science degree
October 2008 - July 2012

Obtained a second-class (upper division) and majored in pure and industrial chemistry

Georgia institute of technology, USA — *online course* April 2020 - June 2020

Participated in an online course on edx.org to learn computer science fundamentals and programming in python.